<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<lfm status="ok"><artist><name>DJ Tiësto</name>
<mbid>aabb1d9f-be12-45b3-a84d-a1fc3e8181fd</mbid>
<url>https://www.last.fm/music/+noredirect/DJ+Ti%C3%ABsto</url>
<image size="small">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/34s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="medium">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/64s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="large">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/174s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="extralarge">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="mega">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<streamable>0</streamable>
<ontour>0</ontour>
<stats><listeners>2045</listeners>
<playcount>31812</playcount>
</stats>
<similar></similar>
<tags><tag><name>trance</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/trance</url>
</tag>
<tag><name>electronic</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/electronic</url>
</tag>
<tag><name>dance</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/dance</url>
</tag>
<tag><name>techno</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/techno</url>
</tag>
<tag><name>electronica</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/electronica</url>
</tag>
</tags>
<bio><links><link rel="original" href="https://last.fm/music/+noredirect/DJ+Ti%C3%ABsto/+wiki"></link>
</links>
<published>02 Feb 2006, 19:23</published>
<summary>Tijs Verwest, known as DJ Tiësto, was born in Breda, the Netherlands. He started DJing professionally at school and house parties in the early 1980s, and then moved on to become a resident DJ between 1985 and 1993 at several clubs in The Netherlands. It was at a club called &apos;The Spock&apos; where things really picked up for Tiësto. He stopped producing hardcore/gabber tracks and started to produce his own sound from 10pm until 4am on weekends. In the mid 1990s, Tiësto started to produce trance and he hasn&apos;t turned back since. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.last.fm/music/+noredirect/DJ+Ti%C3%ABsto&quot;&gt;Read more on Last.fm&lt;/a&gt;</summary>
<content>Tijs Verwest, known as DJ Tiësto, was born in Breda, the Netherlands. He started DJing professionally at school and house parties in the early 1980s, and then moved on to become a resident DJ between 1985 and 1993 at several clubs in The Netherlands. It was at a club called &apos;The Spock&apos; where things really picked up for Tiësto. He stopped producing hardcore/gabber tracks and started to produce his own sound from 10pm until 4am on weekends. In the mid 1990s, Tiësto started to produce trance and he hasn&apos;t turned back since.&#10;&#10;Aliases&#10;He has had many aliases over the years but is most known by the alias DJ Tiësto, although with his recent works he has been known only as Tiësto, dropping the DJ label. His other aliases include: Allure, Da Joker, DJ Limited, Drumfire, Hammock Brothers, Paradise In Dubs, Passenger, Roze, Stray Dog, Tom Ace, and Wild Bunch.&#10;&#10;Claims to Fame&#10;Tiësto has been named an Officer of the Order of Orange-Nassau by the Dutch Royalty, as well as being voted 40th greatest citizen of all time in the Netherlands. He was also crowned #1 DJ for three years in a row (2002, 2003, 2004) by DJ mag readers which is a first for any DJ. He then insisted they pick another DJ, because he thought others deserved a chance as well.&#10;&#10;Famous Tracks&#10;One of Tiësto&apos;s most famous remixes is that of Delerium&apos;s song &quot;Silence&quot;, which was widely popular and still is to date; it was the song that lifted his career and scored him a recording contract with Nettwerk. Other well known tracks of his include &quot;Flight 643&quot;, &quot;Traffic&quot;, &quot;Just Be&quot;, &quot;Sparkles&quot; and his remix of Adagio For Strings, amongst others. &quot;Flight 643&quot; was voted as the second most influential dance track of all time by ID&amp;T fans. &quot;Traffic&quot; was the first instrumental track to reach #1 in the Netherlands in 23 years.&#10;&#10;Concerts&#10;He is well known for his concerts, and his regular slot at the club Amnesia in Ibiza which he got in 2002. Tiësto also played at the 2004 Summer Olympics opening ceremony in Athens, Greece, and released the set on his album Parade of the Athletes. He is also well known for his six hour &quot;Tiësto In Concert&quot; sets, of which he has released two on DVD, including &quot;Tiësto in Concert&quot; in which he became the first DJ ever to play to a sellout crowd of 25,000 people as the only DJ of the night, with no opening or closing act.&#10;&#10;Record Label&#10;In 1997, Tiësto set up a record label with his friend Arny Bink on which his Magik series has been released, known as Black Hole Recordings. There is also a sub-label called Magik Muzik, on which Tiësto continues to sign trance DJs such as Cor Fijneman, DJ Ton TB and Mark Norman.&#10;&#10;Radio&#10;On April 6, 2007 Tiësto began presenting a new weekly two-hour radio show called &quot;Tiësto&apos;s Club Life&quot; on Dutch radio station Radio 538. XM Satellite Radio in the United States later started broadcasting the show on Channel 81 BPM as part of their &quot;Global Domination&quot; lineup on Saturday nights. The show is broadcast on Radio 538 on Friday nights between 22:00 CET and midnight and on BPM on Saturday nights between 8:00 PM EST and 10:00 PM EST. The first hour is also available as a podcast on the Radio 538 website and on iTunes audio podcasts.&#10;&#10;Releases&#10;Tiësto has released four DVDs to date:&#10;Another Day at the Office [Released: 12 August 2003]&#10;Tiësto in Concert [Released: 27 January, 2004]&#10;Tiësto in Concert 2 [Released: 15 February, 2005]&#10;Copenhagen (Elements of Life) [Released: 11 March 2008]&#10;&#10;Tiësto has also released five artist albums to date:&#10;In My Memory [Released: 15 April, 2001]&#10;In My Memory - Remixes [Released: 23 June, 2002]&#10;Just Be [Released: 15 May, 2004]&#10;Parade of the Athletes [Released: 18 October, 2004]&#10;Just Be: Remixed [Released: 27 September, 2005]&#10;Elements Of Life [Released: 10 April, 2007]&#10;Elements of Life Remixed : [Released: April 28 2008]&#10;&#10;Although Tiësto has released 24 remix albums, the following are ones which he is most famous for:&#10;Forbidden Paradise 3 - The Quest For Atlantis [Released: 1995]&#10;Forbidden Paradise 4 - High As A Kite [Released: 1995]&#10;Forbidden Paradise 5 - Arctic Expedition [Released: 1996]&#10;Forbidden Paradise 6 - Valley Of Fire [Released: 1996]&#10;Forbidden Paradise 7 - Deep Forest [Released: 1998]&#10;Magik One - First Flight [Released: 1997]&#10;Magik Two - Story Of The Fall [Released: 1998]&#10;Magik Three - Far From Earth [Released: 1998]&#10;Magik Four - A New Adventure [Released: 1999]&#10;Magik Five - Heaven Beyond [Released: 2000]&#10;Magik Six - Live In Amsterdam [Released: 2000]&#10;Magik Seven - Live In Los Angeles [Released: 2001]&#10;In Search Of Sunrise [Released: 1999]&#10;In Search of Sunrise 2 [Released: 27th February, 2001]&#10;In Search of Sunrise 3 - Panama [Released: 22nd July, 2002]&#10;In Search of Sunrise 4 - Latin America  [Released: 29th April, 2005]&#10;In Search of Sunrise 5 - Los Angeles [Released: 25th April 2006]&#10;In Search of Sunrise 6 - Ibiza [Released: 16th October 2007]&#10;In Search of Sunrise 7 - Asia  [Released:10 June 2008]&#10;Live at Innercity, Amsterdam-Rai [Released: 1999]&#10;Summerbreeze [Released: 2000]&#10;Revolution [Released: 2001]&#10;Nyana [Released: 5th May, 2003]&#10;World Leader [Released: 2003] &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.last.fm/music/+noredirect/DJ+Ti%C3%ABsto&quot;&gt;Read more on Last.fm&lt;/a&gt;. User-contributed text is available under the Creative Commons By-SA License; additional terms may apply.</content>
</bio>
</artist>
</lfm>
