<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<lfm status="ok"><artist><name>Chilli</name>
<mbid>f0697a53-9d82-4e78-a5a1-04aa63e03c14</mbid>
<url>https://www.last.fm/music/Chilli</url>
<image size="small">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/34s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="medium">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/64s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="large">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/174s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="extralarge">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="mega">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<streamable>0</streamable>
<ontour>0</ontour>
<stats><listeners>11534</listeners>
<playcount>55097</playcount>
</stats>
<similar><artist><name>T-Boz</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/music/T-Boz</url>
<image size="small">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/34s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="medium">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/64s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="large">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/174s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="extralarge">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="mega">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
</artist>
<artist><name>Lisa &quot;Left Eye&quot; Lopes</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/music/Lisa+%22Left+Eye%22+Lopes</url>
<image size="small">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/34s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="medium">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/64s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="large">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/174s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="extralarge">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="mega">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
</artist>
<artist><name>Kiley Dean</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/music/Kiley+Dean</url>
<image size="small">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/34s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="medium">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/64s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="large">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/174s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="extralarge">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="mega">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
</artist>
<artist><name>Teairra Mari</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/music/Teairra+Mari</url>
<image size="small">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/34s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="medium">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/64s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="large">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/174s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="extralarge">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="mega">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
</artist>
<artist><name>Yummy Bingham</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/music/Yummy+Bingham</url>
<image size="small">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/34s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="medium">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/64s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="large">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/174s/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="extralarge">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="mega">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
<image size="">https://lastfm.freetls.fastly.net/i/u/300x300/2a96cbd8b46e442fc41c2b86b821562f.png</image>
</artist>
</similar>
<tags><tag><name>rnb</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/rnb</url>
</tag>
<tag><name>female vocalists</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/female+vocalists</url>
</tag>
<tag><name>seen live</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/seen+live</url>
</tag>
<tag><name>tlc</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/tlc</url>
</tag>
<tag><name>soul</name>
<url>https://www.last.fm/tag/soul</url>
</tag>
</tags>
<bio><links><link rel="original" href="https://last.fm/music/Chilli/+wiki"></link>
</links>
<published>05 Jun 2006, 23:43</published>
<summary>There are four artist by the name of Chilli:&#10;&#10;1. Solo artist, member of the band TLC.&#10;&#10;2. An alternative rock band formed in late 1999.&#10;&#10;3. Solo artist from Latvia.&#10;&#10;4. An American dance group assembled in Germany.&#10;&#10;1. Chilli, born Rozonda Ocelean Thomas, was born on February 27th, 1971 in Atlanta, Georgia. Her father, Abdul Ali, was of Arab/Indian descent and her mother, Ava Thomas, was African American. She was teased as a child for her exotic appearance. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.last.fm/music/Chilli&quot;&gt;Read more on Last.fm&lt;/a&gt;</summary>
<content>There are four artist by the name of Chilli:&#10;&#10;1. Solo artist, member of the band TLC.&#10;&#10;2. An alternative rock band formed in late 1999.&#10;&#10;3. Solo artist from Latvia.&#10;&#10;4. An American dance group assembled in Germany.&#10;&#10;1. Chilli, born Rozonda Ocelean Thomas, was born on February 27th, 1971 in Atlanta, Georgia. Her father, Abdul Ali, was of Arab/Indian descent and her mother, Ava Thomas, was African American. She was teased as a child for her exotic appearance. Later she would become one of People&apos;s 50 Most Beautiful People. Her father abandoned her and her mother so she never got a chance to meet her him until 1996 on the Sally Raphael show. She also discovered she had a brother and a sister who now reside with her.&#10;&#10;Chilli did not realize that she wanted to sing until she saw Janet Jackson&apos;s &quot;Control&quot; video and sung along at her job as a teen. In the late &apos;80s, the late Lisa &quot;Left Eye&quot; Lopes and Tionne &quot;T-Boz&quot; Watkins met with Pebbles (read: the wife of La Reid) and formed the group 2nd Nature. After a while the group&apos;s name was changed to TLC, representing members Tionne, Lisa, and Crystal. Crystal was later replaced when L.A. Reid discovered Damian Dame&apos;s dancer Rozonda Thomas. To fit the C, Rozonda was given the name Chilli, because she brought the sauce and the flavor to the group.&#10;&#10;TLC went on to release their playful debut album &apos;Ooooooohhh... On the TLC Tip&apos; which went 3x platinum. Following the huge success of their debut album the group released the more sultry and sensual album &apos;CrazySexyCool&apos;. The album had huge hits such as &quot;Creep&quot;, &quot;Waterfalls&quot;, and &quot;Red Light Special&quot; and went on to sell over 11 million copies worldwide. This is still their most successful album to date. In the midst of recording their new album Chilli had a baby by her longtime boyfriend at the time, producer and friend Dallas Austin. Her son Tron was born on June 3rd, 1997. Their next album &apos;FanMail&apos; followed in the footsteps of their other albums and spawned their huge hit led by Chilli, &quot;No Scrubs&quot;. The R&amp;B single was followed with the Tionne penned pop track, &quot;Unpretty&quot;. The album sold more than 9 million copies worldwide and gave them their first headlining world tour. For the next few years Chilli appeared in many movies including the Nickelodeon film &apos;Snow Day&apos; and VH1&apos;s &apos;A Diva&apos;s Christmas Carol&apos;.. It was also rumored that she began working on a solo debut with Lenny Kravitz and 98 degrees.&#10;&#10;When TLC went to record their 4th LP they were enjoying their time together and Lisa Lopes mentioned it was like the &quot;old days&quot;. Unfortunately, Lisa was killed in a car accident in the Honduras where she went to cleanse her spirit. The project was going to be scrapped in favor of a mournful Greatest Hits album until Chilli and T-Boz decided they wanted to continue with the new LP. The CD, named by Lisa before she passed, was called &apos;3D&apos; and was released in November of 2002. The CD spawned two hits, &quot;Girl Talk&quot; and the pop friendly &quot;Damaged&quot;. A year later they released their greatest hits album &apos;Now and Forever&apos; with new tracks by Dallas Austin and Lil&apos; Jon. In 2004 the group started discussing a reality series to give a fan a chance to appear on a track on a re-released greatest hits album. The talks eventually evolved into the successful reality show &apos;R U the Girl with T-Boz &amp; Chilli&apos; on UPN. The show gave us a look into the life of Rozonda and Tionne and rapper O&apos; So Krispie of Atlanta went on to win the show. The track &quot;I Bet&quot; was recorded but eventually cut by the label. &#10;&#10;Chilli&apos;s solo debut album &apos;Bi-Polar&apos; was scheduled to be released in late 2008 and would have featured production from T-Pain, Akon, Battery 5, and Tricky.  As of the present, there is speculation over &apos;Bi-Polar&apos; ever seeing release, but after performing with T-Boz at a charity concert hosted by Justin Timberlake in 2009, Chilli is focused on a TLC comeback in 2010.  The girls are currently planning their first tour in ten years, and are flirting with the idea of recording a new TLC album.&#10;&#10;&#10;4. A three-piece dance group with American vocalists/dancers, produced in Germany by Frank Farian. After their short-lived worldwide popularity thanks to re-recording Carrapicho&apos;s song Tic, Tic Tac as Chilli feat. Carrapicho, they released a single under their own name in 1998, Say I&apos;m Your No. 1, which was a cover of Raffaella Carrà&apos;s hit, A Far L&apos;Amore Comincia Tu.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.last.fm/music/Chilli&quot;&gt;Read more on Last.fm&lt;/a&gt;. User-contributed text is available under the Creative Commons By-SA License; additional terms may apply.</content>
</bio>
</artist>
</lfm>
